Two worlds. One love.
The Book of Life is a animation, adventure, comedy
film directed by Jorge R. Gutierrez.
The journey of Manolo, a young man who is torn between fulfilling the
expectations of his family and following his heart.
Before choosing which path to follow, he embarks on an incredible adventure that
spans fantastical worlds where he must face his greatest fears.
Manolo (voice), played by Diego Luna.
Joaquin (voice), played by Channing Tatum.
Maria (voice), played by Zoe Saldaña.
Mary Beth (voice), played by Christina Applegate.
Chato (voice), played by Eugenio Derbez.
Pancho Rodriguez (voice), played by Cheech Marin.
The Book of Life is a 2014 American animated fantasy
adventure comedy film directed by Jorge R.
Gutierrez in his feature directorial debut and
written by Gutierrez and Doug Langdale.
Guillermo del Toro, Brad Booker, Aaron D.
Berger and Carina Schulze produced the film.
Produced by 20th Century Fox Animation, Reel FX Animation Studios, and Chatone, it features the voices of Diego Luna, Zoe Saldaña,
and Channing Tatum, with supporting roles from Christina Applegate, Ice Cube, Kate del Castillo, and Ron Perlman.
Based on an original idea by Gutierrez, the film tells the story of Manolo Sánchez (Luna), a bullfighter who wants to be a musician
and win the love of his love interest, María Posada, as he confronts personal challenges on the Day of the Dead.
The Book of Life premiered in Los Angeles on October 12, 2014, and was released
theatrically in the United States on October 17, 2014, by 20th Century Fox.
It received mostly positive reviews from critics and a Golden
Globe nomination for Best Animated Feature Film.
The film grossed $100 million on a $50 million budget.
The film explores themes of mexico, bullfighting, love
triangle, afterlife, day of the dead.
The tone is lighthearted.